Vic Cekvenich

vic@eml.cc NYC, NY http://linkedin.com/in/vic-c

VP Engineering / Director / CTO

Summary:

A seasoned technology executive with experience in team building, innovation, fullstack development and low-code. I love coding and this is an influence on the team.

At the beginning of my career, I worked on performance optimization, then startups and networks. Some highlights over the years include working at NASA, mastering SQL performance, publishing an early book on Java, before switching to front end and web development. I also won trainer of the year by JDJ. The experience I have helps with perspective. I pride self for being a trailblazer, and a web expert. On a personal note: I did a few 'Olympic' triathlons and I am a maintainer of open source project/

<u>Some of the tech I used:</u> Architecture, Agile, CMS, Distributed/Network Computing, HTML5, Pug, CSS, Node.js, Mobile, Java, API, SQL, Video, JAMstack.org.

Github projects: http://github.com/intuition-dev

Professional Experience

- MetaBake.net LLC, NY (Jan. 2017 Present) Managing Partner
 MetaBake LLC is freelance development shop specializing in low-cost low-code development. Consulting, custom development and training- solutions that are maintainable and future safe. Project include a market-product-fit survey.
- Apakau, CA(Oct. 2012 Dec 2016): Principal Engineer/Founder/CTO
 Eliminates the possibility of DDoS attacks via globally deployed Cloud Proxies that intercept HTTP request and accelerate traffic under load without caching, using QOS priority. Tech: Security from DDOS, Java, Node, Architecture, Network/REST/HTTP, Dashboard, HTML5 tech/CSS.
- Rocket Ninja, CA(Jun 2011 Sept. 2012): VP Engineering
 A gaming company working on e-cards, 3D chat and related. Upgraded development process and skills, for example splitting up front end and back end

code. This dramatically improved the competitiveness of the company. Tech: Architecture, Java, ActionScript, HTML5 tech.

- **Akamai**, *CA(Jun 2010 Jun 2011): Sr. Software Engineer*oped video media libraries that are used by professional services and Akamai clients to make efficient and secure media players. Majority of media companies are Akamai customers, including events, like streaming China Olympics. Worked on the key engineering team for streaming. Tech: ActionScript, Java, Architecture, HTML5 tech. One of the projects is open source video player OVP, also DRM, UDP/p2p.
- **Tivo**, CA(Aug 2009 Jun 2010): Sr. Software Engineer

 Next generation embedded consumer product w/ RIA, media content, 3D and social networking. Tech: Embedded device, ActionScript, Java– ex: 'Tivo TV grid'.
- PhoneZoo, CA(Oct 2007- Aug 2009): Architect

PhoneZoo was the dominant mobile teen social networking site. Action-Script, JavaScript, Java and JSP development for a web site catering to a teen social network. Tech: HTML5, Developed widgets, using Java services.

- Vendio (Nov 2006 Oct 2007): CTO; eBay's partner.
- **Keibi** (Feb 2006 Nov 2006): VP Engineering/Co-founder; A start up that would predict bad behavior on social networks to help improve Ad rates.
- baseBeans Engineering (Apr 2001 Jan 2006): Principal Software Engineer; One project was for Ziff-Davis, a gaming social network
- **Novell/SilverStream** (May 1999 April 2001): Sr. Application Engineer; One project was 'Re-engineering the corporation', NASA
- **SEI** TX (1996-99): Instructor; I did vendor certified training in 12 front end and back end public and private courses.
- Computer Science Corporation, TX (1993-95): Sr. Architect; One project was Ford.
- Omnicom/Rapp, NYC(1990-1994): MIS; DB Marketing, dBase, SQL

Education & Credentials

- CUNY Queens College 1990, Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, NYC
- Other:
- - Won Trainer of the Year, by JDJ